# KRISTIN BOWSER

## **UX Researcher & Designer**

ATLANTA, GA 30316
PHONE: 678-634-1397 | EMAIL: KRISTIN.K.BOWSER@GMAIL.COM
LINKEDIN: WWW.LINKEDIN/COM/IN/KRISTINBOWSER | PORTFOLIO: WWW.BEHANCE.NET/KRISTINBOWSER

### **SUMMARY**

User Experience Researcher leveraging a background in L&D and communication in a UX career. Known as an excellent communicator with a knack for understanding how to interact with people from many backgrounds. A passion for details, human behavior, and communication allows me to have a particular affinity for UX research and writing in professional endeavors and organizations.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Design Skills: Research | Design thinking | Agile planning | A/B testing | Usability testing | Comparative research | Style guide creation | Wireframing | Prototyping | Human behavior | Communication | Team projects

Tools: Adobe XD | Miro | Slack | Google Drive | Trello | InVision

Interviewing: Stakeholders & Users

Programming: HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | JQuery | Bootstrap

### **UX/UI PROJECTS**

### <u>Circle of Friends Animal Society Redesign</u>

Redesign of the web and mobile sites for COFAS, a non-profit pet adoption organization. The end-result was a high-fidelity design created using Adobe XD.

#### My Role

Primary researcher, in charge of stakeholder contact, persona creation, interviewing, problem/solution creation, and pulling key user insights.

Link: https://tinyurl.com/ya5c3yyw

### **GetGreen Mobile Application**

The task was designing a mobile app that would benefit the world. We chose to create a gamification app aimed at encouraging users to 1. shop small and 2. be incentivized to participate in sustainable behaviors.

#### My Role

Primary researcher, in charge of stakeholder contact, persona creation, interviewing, problem/solution creation, and pulling key user insights.

Link: https://tinyurl.com/yabywcwu

### **Bootcamp Spot Redesign**

An open-design challenge - redesigning the learning management platform used in the Georgia Tech UX/UI Professional Bootcamp.

#### My Role

Primary researcher, in charge of persona creation, interviewing, problem/solution creation, and pulling key user insights. Largely designed the mobile prototype and style guide.

**Link:** https://tinyurl.com/y9f5co7o

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Learning & Development Manager

Shepard Exposition Services | Atlanta, GA | 2018-2020

Designed & built the company's Learning & Development department from the ground up using UX Design thinking along with stakeholder & employee surveys to identify training needs & build programming.

### **Major Accomplishments**

- Successfully researched, designed, & presented original & curated leadership & training content for 20-30% of employees & managers in the first year of L&D management
- Onboarded 60 new employees using the 30-60-90 day onboarding plan that was created based on feedback from surveys and focus groups

#### **Human Resources Generalist**

Shepard Exposition Services | Atlanta, GA | 2016-2018

Transitioned a traditional labor relations department to a fully functioning Human Resources department focused on recruiting, wellness initiatives, employee relations, performance management, & HRIS technology.

### **Major Accomplishments**

- Saw an increase of 70% participation in performance reviews by creating an intuitive review form & project managing the launch of a digital review platform.
- Recruited & onboarded nearly 200 full/part-time employees in two years

### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Recruiting Coordinator
CHILDREN'S HEALTHCARE OF ATLANTA
2015-2016

HR & Recruiting Coordinator
DIGITAS (DIGITAL AD AGENCY IN SAN FRANCISCO)
2014-2015

HR & Recruiting Coordinator
INFORM (SAAS COMPANY IN ATLANTA)
2013-2014

### **EDUCATION**

Georgia Institute of Technology
CERTIFICATE IN UX/UI DESIGN, 2020

The University of Georgia

BACHELOR OR ARTS IN DIGITAL & BROADCAST
JOURNALISM, CLASS OF 2012